# DANIEL HUMPHRIES

WWW.AUFBAU.IO // DAN@AUFBAU.IO Haggerston  $\diamond$  London  $\diamond$  UK

### PROFILE SUMMARY

Fullstack software engineer. Specialised in creative and technical engineering. Ethical and sustainable roles only.

#### **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

Software & Tools Language: Python // JavaScript // Rust // Haskell // SQL // C/C++

Front-end: Svelte // React // Vue // Three JS // WebGL // WebGPU
Back-end: Supabase // Flask // Docker // PostgreSQL // MongoDB
Full-stack: GCP // AWS // Linux // GraphQL // Blender // PyTorch

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

. .

AufbauOctober 2022 - PresentFounder // Web Engineer (Freelance)London, UK

· Creative Web Engineering // WebGL Specialist // Bespoke Websites, Systems, & Apps - from scratch.

· Tech Stack: SvelteKit // Three JS // Supabase // Rust // WebGL // Web GPU // Python // Javascript

VSProwess January 2023 - Present

Graphics Engineer (Contract)

London, UK

- · Building a bespoke 3d data renderer in Rust/C++. Rendering 1e6 1e9 voxels simultaneously and interactively.
- · Tech Stack: Rust // C++ // WebGPU // Dawn

Midnight Agency

March 2022 - Present

 $Senior\ Full stack\ Engineer\ (Contract\ /\ Freelance)$ 

London, UK

- · Senior Fullstack engineer within a creative technology web agency. Autonomous position among technical leads.
- · Tech Stack: Svelte // React // Three JS // Next // Vercel // Docker // CMS // WebGL

November 2021 - February 2022

 $London,\ UK$ 

Senior Fullstack Engineer (Contract)

- · Fullstack developer. Contracted to take start-up from prototype to app store release. Scoped, hired, and led a team (react native developer and junior developer) to deliver a robust and scalable application within 4 months.
- · Tech Stack: React Native // Next // GCP // Apollo // GraphQL // Docker // Firebase

Kubrick Group

July 2020 - August 2021

London, UK

Fullstack Software Engineer

- · Fullstack software engineer on a greenfield community learning platform. Vue.js and Nuxt app deployed on AWS.
- · First Project engineer. Hired and led technical team to take product from concept to MVP with DevOps strategy.
- · Tech Stack: Nuxt // Vue // D3 // Python // PostgreSQL // MongoDB // AWS // Docker

Procter & Gamble

November 2018 - June 2020

Reading, UK

Machine Learning Engineer

- · Engineer and co-architect on a microservice-based data network & machine learning platform. Bespoke system enabled large multinational to run distributed machine learning models on data assets stored across continents.
- · Tech Stack: Python // Vue // Flask // Celery // Docker // PostgreSQL // MongoDB // CUDA // Linux

### **EDUCATION**

## University College London

September 2014 - May 2018 MSci Neuroscience London, UK

- · Course of study focused on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience and Dynamical Systems.
- · Masters Dissertation: 'Dendritic Spine Stability during Regulative Homeostasis' with Prof Tara Keck
- · Bachelors Dissertation: 'Neural Oscillatory Rhythms: Physics & Function' with Dr Lorenzo Fabrizi

# Kings College London

MA Philosophy

September 2021 - September 2022 London, UK

- · Course of study focused on Kant, Mind, Meta-Metaphysics, Communication, and Representation.
- · Masters Dissertation: 'Carving the Mind at its Joints' with Prof Bill Brewer

# RESEARCH

## University College London

October 2022 - Present

Systems Enginer // Research Assistant

London, UK

- · Working with Dr Daniel Bush and Prof. Neil Burgess on topics in spatial representation and neuroinformatics.
- · Building a real-time, closed-loop stimulation system for manipulating Sharp-Wave Ripples in human subjects.

# University of Oxford

July 2021 - Present

Fullstack Engineer // Research Assistant

Oxford, UK

- · Creating a mental state tracking tool with Dr. Dan Joyce, a computational and clinical psychiatrist.
- · Lightweight and customisable tool to facilitate psychiatric research on the dynamics of mental state over time.

## **OTHER**

Raumen Bar August 2022 - Present

London Space and Representation Reading Group

London, UK

- · Articles and research on space, action, and representation across neuroscience, philosophy, and mathematics.
- · Current members from UCL, Gatbsy, SWC & KCL. Always open to new members, reach out !!

## Bartlett School of Architecture

July 2021 - September 2022

Computational Soul: Guest Seminar

London, UK

- · Invited to run guest seminar on 'computational soul' as part of the Xalon Digital-Communities lecture series.
- · Discussed the notions of soul and representation in objects, and what it takes to synthesise 'computational soul'.

### Metamodernism as a Service

December 2020 - September 2021

AI-Generated Poetry Series

London, UK

- · Computer generated 'poetry' made with the early GPT-3 demo API. Exploring notions of self in artifical agents.
- · 3AM Bauhaus-FM radio perfomance with Vivien Jester in Weimar, Germany. Gallery show in Portland, USA.